LEGO Frozen Northern Lights is a animation, family film directed by None.
Elsa, Anna and friends search for the Northern Lights.
Anna (voice), played by Kristen Bell.
Girl Troll (voice), played by Ashlyn Faith Williams.
Olaf (voice), played by Josh Gad.
Kristoff (voice), played by Jonathan Groff.
Elsa (voice), played by Idina Menzel.
Sven (voice), played by Frank Welker.
Frozen is a Disney media franchise started by the 2013 American animated feature film Frozen, which was directed by Chris Buck and Jennifer Lee,
screenplay by Lee and produced by Peter Del Vecho, music score by Christophe Beck, and songs written by Robert Lopez and Kristen Anderson-Lopez.
John Lasseter, then-chief creative officer of Walt Disney Animation
Studios, served as the film's executive producer.
The original film was inspired by Hans Christian
Andersen's fairy tale, "The Snow Queen".
Since the film's release in November 2013, the
franchise has expanded very rapidly.
To date, the franchise includes various Disney theme park attractions, merchandise, toys, video games,
books, a Disney on Ice show, a Broadway stage musical and two short animated films.
Disney also released Frozen 2 in 2019, and a new book series.
In November 2014, TheStreet.com explained that "Frozen is no longer a movie, it's a global brand, a larger than
life franchise built around products, theme parks and sequels that could last into the next century".
Boxoffice chief analyst Phil Contrino was quoted
as saying "it's become massive".
The franchise is one of the highest-grossing media franchises of all time.